Okay, so let's talk about some of the
PIMBOC guide processes in risk management,
and of course, again, as related to PIMBOC
version 6.
So we can see then there are seven
processes, right, in the PIMBock guide,
right, when it comes to risk management.
It's then the span planning, executing and
monitoring controlling.
Right, so in planning then, you have plan
risk management, right?
So again, the very first process of any of
the not.
knowledge areas from scope management all
the way down, look at the process map,
right, the process grid.
The first process is always going to be
plan something management.
So in this case, plan risk management.
And the output, right, the artifact that
we're creating here, the output of plan
risk management management is the risk
management plan.
And the risk management plan, there's a
separate video on that where we're talking
about, or rather where
we'll be discussing what
we're going to be documenting
in the risk management.
plan.
Again, remember, it's always procedures.
It's always how we're going to plan,
execute, monitoring control, in this case,
the risk management knowledge area.
Then another process is this one called
identify risk.
Throughout your project, you're going to
be identifying risk.
And so where are we going to document
them?
Once we've identified a risk, where do you
document them?
You're going to document them in the risk
register.
So the output, if you
like, the artifact that we're
creating the output of
identify risk is the risk register.
And the risk register will contain all the
details, the probability, the impact,
what's going to trigger it, who's a risk
owner, and so on and so forth,
all documented in the risk register.
Then we have these next two
processes here, perform qualitative
risk analysis and perform
quantitative risk analysis.
Now, be very careful with these two,
right?
If you look, the wording looks very
similar, the spelling looks very similar,
but they are two very different processes.
This is perform, the first one here,
113, is perform qualitative risk analysis.
And the other one is perform quantitative
risk analysis.
Both of these are analyzing
your risk, but they're
looking at them in
slightly different ways.
With qualitative, you are analyzing your
risk using arbitrary values, like high,
medium low, scale of 1 to 10, or red,
yellow green classification, right?
or whatever unit of measure, whatever
arbitrary value your organization uses,
that's qualitative.
So you're ranking your risk, prioritizing
your risk based on some arbitrary value.
With quantitative, that was qualitative.
With quantitative, you are adding a dollar
value to your risk.
So there's a subtle difference.
I won't say a cell.
There's a major difference there.
With quantitative, you are adding a dollar
value to your risk.
Then, in this process, we're going to be
talking about calculating the EMV,
expected monetary values.
And then once we've performed all of
these, we've done all the analysis,
we've identified the risk,
analyzed the risk, then
we need to figure out
how to respond to the risk.
The other process here then in planning is
plan risk responses.
As part of execution, right, once you've
planned, you've planned, you.
your risk responses, you need to implement
the risk response.
So that's what the implement risk response
refers to.
And then you're monitoring controlling,
right?
Remember, monitoring
controlling is always comparing
actual results from
executing with your plan.
So how did we respond to the risk?
You know, what lessons learned are there?
How could we improve in the future?
Did we respond the way we expected to
respond and so on and so forth?
So these are all the
different processes then in
risk management as it
relates to the PIMBOC guide.